感谢大家
Thank you guys so much.
也很荣幸今天能站在这里
This is really awesome to be on the stage today.
过去的几年  我花了大量的时间
Over the past year, I've spent a lot
来谈论Web component
of time talking about web components,
传授开发者以基本的开发标准
really teaching developers the basics of the standards
以及教人们如何去专注于构建elements
and teaching folks how to focus on building elements.
此时此刻
And we're now at this place where
我们有一个蓬勃发展的elements生态系统
we have this burgeoning ecosystem of elements that are out there.
在开源社区也有很多的开发者
There's a lot of developers out in the open source world
他(她)们在创作elements的同时
who are creating elements but also got
也享受着由Polymer团队开发的element集合所带来的便利
element sets that have been created by the Polymer team.
我们有core和paper elements
We've got the core and the paper elements.
所以说 在这一点上
And so we're at this point where we
我们正处在蓬勃发展的生态系统之中
have this flourishing ecosystem and I
我想是时候让我们开始思考
think it's time for us to start to think
我们的下一个挑战 那就是
about the next challenge, which is how do we leverage that
如何利用这个生态系统开发出实际的应用
ecosystem to actually build real applications.
我对如何在移动应用上创造出让人流连忘返的体验
And I'm particularly interested in figuring out
非常之感兴趣
how to build compelling experiences on mobile.
移动互联网拥有着大量的机遇
The mobile web has a ton of opportunity,
而对于Web开发者来说
but it's one of those areas where for web developers,
如何在移动端上创造出真正让人流连忘返的体验
it's always been a challenge to create
一直都是一个挑战
a real compelling experience on a mobile device.
所以 当我准备这个演讲的时候 我要做的
And so when I was preparing for this talk, what I wanted to do
仅仅是掏出我的手（爪）机 翻看那些
was just like pop my phone out and look at the applications
我也一直在使用的  那些我认为
that I use all the time, things I
成功的带给人以流连忘返体验类型的应用
consider sort of successful experiences.
我想在它们的身上
And I wanted to go through them and just sort of catalog what
找到作为一个成功的应用程序
I see as the kind of common UI and UX expectations
应有的UI和UX影子
in a successful app.
在这里有Twitter
So what I've got here is Twitter,
我安装Pocket Cast用来听播客
I've got Pocket Cast for listening to podcasts,
并且 还有RDO
and I've got RDO.
使我感到吃惊的事是
And one thing that struck me as I was doing this
当我把这些应用并排开来的时候
is if I just take these applications
尽管我知道把每一个应用都孤立开来看时
and I put them side by side, even though each of them
会给人与众不同的感觉
kind of feels unique when I'm looking at it in isolation,
但当我把它们一字排开
when they're all lined up like that,
仿佛感觉他们的界面
it feels like they're just like a ton of commonalities
都是如出一辙的
in their interfaces.
在此拿Twitter为例
And so using Twitter as an example here,
我想要做的仅仅是把这些常用的UI编录到一起
I want to just catalog some of those common UI patterns that I see.
比如在顶端 会有一个工具栏
So up at the top, we have a toolbar.
非常面熟呢
Pretty familiar.
而且一般的话  如果你创建了个工具栏
And oftentimes, if you've got a toolbar,
你将会用一些图标按钮对其进行填充
you're going to fill it up with some icon buttons.
往下一点儿  是一些选项卡
And below that, you've got some tabs
目的是用来进行内容间的切换
for switching between content.
这里是主要内容区域
You've got a primary content area,
而且一般情况下
and oftentimes, you're going to have
都会有无尽的内容列表在里面
like an infinite list of contents inside of there,
或者你仅仅是想在用户向下翻页时
or you might just be lazy loading more content
延迟加载更多的内容
as the user is scrolling down the page.
最后在底部  会有一个次级工具栏
And down at the bottom, you've got a secondary toolbar
用来做一些额外的操作
for doing additional actions of some kind.
现在  如果我们坐上时空穿梭机
Now, if we take a step back again
回到把它们联结起来的那个状态
and we line these apps up again, like when
也就是刚才打量Twitter的时候
I was looking at Twitter a moment ago,
这种体验感觉非常奇特
it felt like a very unique experience.
不仅名称不同
It felt kind of aligned with its brand
而且各司其职
and it had kind of its own thing going on.
但当我把这些应用再次并排放在一起的时候
But again, I line these guys up and I
我发现它们都有着相似的UI模式
can see that they all kind of have those same UI patterns going on.
做着同样的工作
They're all kind of doing the exact same thing.
而它们之所以看着相似的原因
And the reason they all look the same
那就是它们都是通过一个SDK开发的
is because they're all built using an SDK.
所有的这些都是来自Android平台的例子
So these are examples coming from Android,
而这些例子在iOS平台上也同样适用
but the same is true if you're working in iOS.
如果你在其中任意的一个平台开发应用的话
If you're building on one of those platforms,
SDK都是现成的
you already have this SDK that's available to you,
其中的组件一抓一大把
grab a bunch of components out of it.
也许你只是稍作调整  改变一下它们的颜色
Maybe you kind of tweak them a little bit, color them differently.
但是总体上说 组建你应用的原材料
But in general, you're using stuff
都是预先准备好的
that's already available to compose your application.
而现在  在Web开发方面  我们从未拥有过任何此类的东西
Now, on the web, we've kind of never really had this thing.
更没有用于应用开发的原型
We've never had app building primitives.
我们也从来没有一个移动端的SDK
We've never had a mobile web SDK,
我想是时候改变一下这种状态
and I think it's time for that to change.
并且我觉得真正能够胜任这种改变的
And I really think that the way that we're
应该就是使用Polymer和Web组件了
going about doing this is using Polymer and Web Components.
所以 我今天的目的就是要教你
So my goal today is to teach you how to build mobile web
如何利用这些新技术去开发移动端的应用程序
applications using these new technologies.
基本上  我把这节分为四个部分
And I basically split this up into four parts.
第一部分 我将像你展示
[? The very ?] part, I'm going to show you just
怎样为你的应用程序构建UI
how you can structure the UI for your application,
接下来我们将要看看  如何才能
then we're going to look at how you can transition from one
从应用的一个状态过渡到另外一个状态
state of your application to the next.
此后  我们将专注于
After that, we're going to look at ways
如何优化应用的性能
to make sure your application is performant, because that's
因为对于移动应用来说  这至关重要
really crucial for a mobile application.
最后的最后 让我们谈谈
And lastly, we're going to look at ways
如何确保你的应用在不联网的情况下也可使用
you can make sure your application runs offline
因为如果你的移动应用不能做到脱机可用的话
because if your mobile app doesn't run offline,
那根本就算不上是移动应用
then you really don't have a mobile app.
人们经常在无网或者是网络不好的情况下
People are oftentimes on their mobile devices
使用移动设备
when they're in low connectivity to no connectivity situations.
所以说能够离线可用
So it's got to run offline for it
是创造一个给人以流连忘返体验应用的一个前提
to be a real, compelling mobile app experience.
先从Structure讲起
Let's start with structure and just think about ways
试着思考我们为自己应用撰写UI时的方式
that we can compose the UI for our application.
是的  关键词就在这  compose
And really, that's the key word here-- compose.
我将要做的就是从Polymer的core elements以及paper elements集合中
What I want to do is I'm going to take as many preexisting
获取一些先前已经存在的element
elements from the Polymer core sets to the paper sets
并把它们栓在一起 来开发我的应用
and I want to bolt them together to build my application.
这是今天我们将要开发的应用
So this is the app that we're going
只是一个简单的联系人通讯录应用
to be working from today, just a really simple contacts app
把那些element联合在了一起
that I threw together.
并且我尽量试着采用不少和先前  我所讲过的
And I'm trying to utilize a lot of the same patterns
那些成功应用相同的样式
that I was showing in the previous successful apps that I had before.
工具栏上有图标按钮
So you've got the toolbar at the top with some icon buttons.
你开始上下滚动
You start scrolling around, you're
为了查看这无尽列表里面的内容
going to get this sort of infinite list of content inside of there.
这有一个抽屉面板  你可以弹出菜单
You've got a drawer panel that you can pop out for your menu.
点击其中任意一个联系人
Clicking on any one of the contacts
会有一个过渡动画
is going to do kind of like an animated transition
向你展示详细的联系人信息
to show you that person's contact details.
随着我来回滚动
I get it's really nice, cool condensing header effect
会有非常棒的condensing header效果
as I scroll around.
并且这还有一个浮动的动作按钮
And also, I've got a little floating action button
在底部
down there in the corner.
点击这个按钮  弹出并打开另一个界面
I can click that, pop open another screen.
这些就是我所使用的全部过渡动画效果
These are all animated transitions that I'm using here.
如果你之前听过我的演讲的话
Now, if you've seen me talk before,
你可能已经见过我在开发应用的过程中
you've probably seen me start off by using this element.
以使用这个element作为开始
Anytime I'm building an application,
你也可能会感觉
it seems like I'm always starting off
我经常会以core toolbar element作为开始
with this core toolbar element, which
虽说它仅仅只是一个非常基本的容器
is just a really simple container.
它规定了其子element使用Flexbox布局模式
It lays out its children using Flexbox
这也是你迈出第一步的
and it's a really good place to get
绝佳去处
started with one of your screens.
而且因为composition才是今天真正的主角
And because composition is really
所以我想要做的第一件事就是
the name of the game, what I want to do first
把一些我想要的额外的element放在这里面
is I want to just throw some additional elements
为我的工具栏来构造UI
inside of here, and I just want to compose the UI for my toolbar.
所以我把一个paper icon button放在了那
So I've dropped a paper icon button inside of there.
赋予其图标属性
I've configured it with an icon attribute
用以实现hamburger菜单按钮的效果
to give me the hamburger menu from that application,
以便稍后我滑动屏幕呼出菜单项
and so I'm going to slide out my menu later.
这里有一个div属性
I've also dropped a div inside of here
来实现应用的标题显示
for the title of my application.
而现在  关于core toolbar最酷的事情之一
Now, one of the cool things about the core toolbar
就是它使用Flexbox的布局模式 极大地简化了底层CSS Flexbox的部署
is that since it uses Flexbox, I can kind of
我们可以借坡下驴 利用其一些优势
take advantage of that a little bit.
在Polymer中称这些东西为布局属性
There's things called layout attributes in Polymer,
而我所能做的事情就是
and what I can do is I can actually
告诉我的工具栏标题
tell the title of my toolbar that I
我希望它能尽可能的
want it to flex to take up as much space is
填充工具栏里面的空间
it can inside of the toolbar.
这是个易用的技巧
This is a really handy trick to know
因为它意味着
because it means that I can then pin controls
我可以pin control工具栏侧边
to the other side of my toolbar.
我想要做的其实是添加一个背景菜单
What I want to do here is actually add a little context menu so I can
这样我才能有类似于设置以及反馈啊之类的东西
have things like settings and feedback.
为了实现那个 我将要用另外一个element
So to do that, I'm going to use another element called
它叫做paper-menu-button
paper-menu-button, and paper-menu-button's
它本身非常的有趣  因为它
pretty interesting because by itself, it really
真的木有做任何事情
doesn't do anything.
它是无用的
It's kind of useless.
如果你只是把paper-menu-button标签
If you just put a paper-menu-button tag
放在页面上  真的是什么作用也木有
on the page, you get really nothing.
它仅仅是在你开始compose它里面的
It only really comes into its own
其他elements时才发挥其作用
when you start composing other elements inside of it.
这是一个待解锁的潜在技能
That's really how you unlock the potential of it.
所以我现在在那里
So I've got another paper icon button
创建了另一个paper icon button
that I've thrown inside of here, and that's
用来让用户点击
going to give the user something to click on.
然后我把paper drop down放在
Then I'm going to throw in a paper drop down,
paper icon button下面
and that's going to give me this little animated rectangle
在这里实现一个小矩形动画
thing up there.
所以  当菜单展开的时候
So when the menu expands, it's going
它仿佛就像从角落里走出来一样
to kind of like come out from the corner,
朝向页面的中心展开
expand towards the center of the site.
其中的halign属性
The halign attribute that I've thrown
是为了标明动画该从哪个方向开始
on there is going to indicate which direction it should animate from.
所以在这里  我们定义的动画方向
So here, we're telling it to animate
是从页面的右边缘延伸至屏幕中央
from the right edge towards the center of the screen.
最后  我在这里面放一个core menu
Lastly, I'm going to throw a core menu inside of here,
实现一些类似于Feekback接收用户反馈之类的
and that's going to give me the actual menu items that users
这样的实际菜单项
are going to select for my sending them feedback.
现在  让人感到欣慰的事是
Now, the cool thing here is that each
每一个我放在paper menu button里面的element
of those elements that I threw inside of my paper menu button
其自身都是有用的了
is useful on its own.
通过使用core menu我可以在页面的其它地方创建菜单  如果我需要一个菜单的情况下
I can use core menu elsewhere my site if I need a menu.
这简直棒极了
What's awesome, though, is when I
当我开始把这些东西组合在一起的时候
start to compose these things together,
我获得了很多不同又十分有趣的复杂效果
I get different interesting complex behaviors.
而且还有重要的一点要指出
And it's also important to point out
我没有写任何的CSS或JavaScript代码 来实现这一效果
that I didn't write any CSS or JavaScript to make this happen.
我仅仅是把这些捏合到一起 oh yay
I just nipped together these-- oh, yay.
谢谢
Thank you, [? Demetri ?].
这些element知道如何一起工作
These elements just know how to work together
因为它们是应用开发原型 酷极了
because they're app building primitives, which is awesome.
一旦我对我自己工具栏的外观非常的满意
And once I'm happy with the look of my toolbar,
那么接下来我们把所有的标记
then you take all of this markup and I could throw it inside
放进另一个叫core-header-panel的element里
of another element called core-header-panel.
core-header-panel仅仅是一个包含标题区和内容区的简单容器
And the core-header-panel is just a really simple container.
标题区默认保持在页面的顶部
It's got a header section up at the top, which
内容则在其下方
will hold the toolbar, content area down below.
并且对于core-header-panel来说 很酷的事情是
And the cool thing about the core header panel
它仅仅只专注于管理
is it only really cares about managing the scroll behavior
应用的滚动行为
from my application.
如果我把工具栏放在core-header-panel 里面
If I put a toolbar inside of it, it's
它会确保工具栏
going to make sure that that toolbar stays
一直都贴附在文档的顶部
sticky up there at the top of the document
而且其他的内容只在它的底下移动
and all my other content is just going to move underneath it.
再一次  没有写任何CSS及JavaScript的代码
Again, no CSS or JavaScript to make this happen.
因为这些都是聪明的原型
These are just smarter primitives.
它们知道如何像刚才那样一起工作
They know how to work together like that.
现在  假设有人在点开我其中的一个联系人
Now, when someone's actually looking at one of my contacts,
我想要有像这个一样酷酷的Addy Osmani的头像封面效果
I want to have this cool, big shot of Addy Osmani's face
从根本上说  是我想实现这样的漂亮动画效果
basically, and I want it to do this cool animating effect.
随着联系人向下滚动
So as the person is scrolling down,
页面开始渐渐折叠
it kind of collapses, and it's sort
与此同时  伴随着背景图片微微开始淡入淡出
of crossfading with the background image.
为了实现这个  我使用了一个core-header-panel的表亲类
And to do that, I'm using a cousin of the core-header-panel
叫作core-scroll-header-panel
called the core-scroll-header-panel.
它们基本上是相同的组件
It's basically the same component,
但是core-scroll-header-panel增添了很棒的condenses属性
but it adds this nice condenses attribute,
所以才有刚刚这种酷炫的效果
and it gives me that kind of cool effect.
而现在我的移动应用已经有了不同的  我所喜欢的界面
Now, once I have the different screens for my mobile site laid
而接下来我要把所有的这些都放进
out in a way that I like them, I can drop all of this
另一个叫core-drawer-panel的element里面
into another element called core-drawer-panel,
目的是为移动端和桌面端
and that's going to give me a responsive
构建响应式框架
scaffold for desktop and mobile.
而且这个element生效的方式  一般是有个抽屉区
And the way this element works, it's basically got a drawer area.
所有放在里面的内容
Any content that I place inside of there
都以侧边栏作为结尾
is going to end up in my sidebar.
这是主内容区
It's got a main area.
所有放在主内容区里的内容
Any content that I place inside of there
都以次级内容去作为结尾
ends up in the primary content area.
值得的鼓舞的是  该element默认是响应式
And the cool thing is, this element is responsive by default.
如果我在桌面平台上开始向外拖拽
So if I'm on my desktop and I just start dragging it out,
你会看到这边抽屉面板已经打开
you'll see the drawer panel opens there.
我可以尽情的进行开和关
I can open and close it.
继续拖拽 到了一个预设的大小
I drag this thing out, and when I hit a certain size,
工具栏会自动弹出
the toolbar just pops out for me.
非常的棒
This is really nice.
又一次 我没有写任何断点或者是CSS media queries
Again, I'm not writing any breakpoints or media queries
就让此得以实现
to make this happen.
element默认就是响应式的  棒棒哒
The element's just responsive by default, which is really nice.
现在 我已经把应用的骨架建造好了
Now, at this point, I've built the skeleton of an application.
我已经向你展示了  如何建好外壳
I've kind of shown you how to put the shell
但是我们的应用程序依然缺少着
around everything, but what we're still missing
一个关键命脉
is the lifeblood of our application.
我们落下了内容
We're missing the content.
并且  之前在我展示这些应用的时候
And when I'm showing these apps earlier,
我一直在说  这些应用将要做的事情是
I mentioned that oftentimes what they're going to do
像一个无尽的表一样
is they're going to do like an infinite list,
亦或是延迟加载 所以用户才能让他们的推文
or of a lazy load of content so the user can
也可以是相册或者其他之类的东西
keep scrolling through all of their tweets,
一直从头到尾  来回滚动
or all of their albums, and things like that,
我们可以通过一个叫core-list的element
and we can achieve the same thing in our application using
在我们的应用上实现相同的效果
an element called core-list.
core-list也是我最喜爱的element之一
And core-list is one of my favorite elements
因为从某种程度上说  我觉得
because I feel like it's sort of the thing that
core-list把所有的框架和内容
knits all the scaffolding and the content
都用我喜爱的方式  编结到了一起
together in this way that I really love.
core-list是一个虚拟化的infinite list
The core-list is basically a virtualized infinite list.
当你把它和data provider连接起来  然后它会为在data provider数组里面的
You connect it to a data provider and then it stamps out a template
每一个single instance压制出一个template
for every single instance in that data provider's array.
所以在这里list.data等于some array
So here, I'm saying list.data equals some array.
array数组里面有一些对象
I've got objects inside of that array.
每一个对象对应着一个名字
Each of those objects has a name.
并且在core-list里面  有一个template element
And inside my core-list, I have a template element
我只是将其绑定起来
and I'm just binding to each of those instances as they come in.
创造出高效的infinite list
It gives me this really, really performant infinite list
这样就能遍历所有联系人
so I can go through all of my contacts.
在我开发应用的过程中
Now, as I was building my application,
我遇到了这样一件事
I kind of came across this thing--
在此作为一个建议和你们一起分享
which I'm going to share with you as a tip
如果你开始使用core-list的话
if you want to go out and start using core-list yourself.
需要注意的是core-list会回收其子元素
One of things that core-list does is it recycles its children.
这也是它为何性能出众的原因
That's actually how it's so performant.
在子元素移动过程中  core-list会使其固定
It makes a fixed set of children and as they're moving,
然后再用其他的方式把它们打回原形
it's pulling them back around the other way.
所以如果在core-list里有图像标签的话
So if you have image tags inside of your core-list,
在与网络赛跑的过程中就会败下阵来
you can end up in a situation where you're basically
过期的图像会在屏幕上下横飞
racing the network and you're having stale images fly
要等一会才能及时刷新
past the screen, and then they catch up
看起来怪怪的
and change, which sort of looks weird.
我发现这有一个叫做core-image的element
So I found that there's an element called core-image
通过它你可以防止应用加载过期的图像
which you can use to prevent stale images in your application.
这非常的简单
It's pretty easy.
你只需把它嵌套在这里
You just drop it in here.
给它一个preload属性
You give it a preload attribute, and what
这样它就会告诉应用
that does is it says, hey, if I'm loading an image,
hey  如果我正在加载图像
I'm not going to display the stale image that
我是不会去显示之前这的过期图像的
perhaps was inside of here before.
我只会显示一些背景颜色
I'm just going to display a little background color.
所以我们才能得以
And so what we can do now is we can actually
有这样炫酷的联系人列表
have this cool contacts list.
我们在和网络赛跑
We can sort of race the networking
你可以看见这些图片一直在加载
and you can see the images loading in,
但是你看不见过期的图像  这非常的棒
but what you're not seeing is stale images, which is good.
在开发过程中我发现的另一件重要的事是
The other thing that I discovered as I was doing this
确保将core-list的scrollTarget
is that it's really important to make sure to set your core-list
设置到core-header-panel-scroller上
scroll target to your core-header-panel-scroller.
我想这理解上可能会有点困难
I know that this is a little bit of a rough edge,
但是我希望大家能意识到一点
but I wanted to make you guys aware of it
如果你开始使用这个
if you're going to go out and start hacking on these things today.
内部流程基本是这个样子
Basically what happens when you do
core-list这个element
this is you're telling the core-list
会监听由core-header-panel发出的scroll事件
to listen to the scroll events that the core header panel is
它们俩可以彼此和睦的玩耍在一起
firing and that way, the two can work together in harmony.
现在  你可以通过两种方式实现这个
Now, there's two ways that you can go about doing this.
你可以在JavaScript里指定scroll target
You can either set the scroll target in JavaScript.
像这样list.scrollTarget=hPanel.scroller
You could say list.scrollTarget equals hPanel.scroller,
或者你也可以通过数据绑定这种神奇的方式
or you can do this with bindings if you want to be really fancy
来惊艳观众
and impress your friends.
即scrollTarget=hPanel.scroller
You could just say scrollTarget equals hPanel.scroller.
再一次
Now, this is one of those things which, again,
现在听起来可能会有些晦涩难懂
I think it's a little bit of a rough edge.
在未来  我们也许会让其变得更加简洁
Perhaps we might be able to clean this up in the future
这样就不用手动去把它们链接到一起了
so that you don't have to wire this up yourself,
这应该引起大家的注意
but I wanted to make you aware of it
因为我们要做的第一件事
because it was like the first thing I wanted to do
就是把这些list中的某个
was put one of those lists inside of one
放入某个header中  我需要设置个链接
of those fancy headers, and I needed
好把它们都连接起来  这样才能生效
to set up this linkage to make it all work.
至此  成功运用composition的魅力
Now, through the beauty of composition, I've taken my list
我们得以把list放入了scaffold里
and I've thrown it inside of my scaffold,
打造出这一炫酷应用
and I have this really, really cool application now.
现在  让我们简单概括一下这都有什么
Now, I want to give you a quick recap of what we have inside of here.
在顶端  有个core-toolbar
So up0 at the top, I've got a core toolbar.
其次有paper-icon-button和paper-menu-button
After that, a paper-icon-button, a paper-menu-button
在联系人菜单里
for my contacts menu.
这有一个core-header-panel
I've got a core-header-panel, which
控制主页的滚动行为
is controlling the scroll behavior for my home page.
还有core-drawer-panel
I've got a core-drawer-panel, which
构建响应式布局
gives me that responsive scaffolding
所以才能在桌面和移动端都能使用
so it works on desktop and mobile,
以及和Infinite content provider彼此绑定的core-list
and I've got a core list for my infinite content provider.
有意思的是
Now, one thing that's really cool
一旦你开始感觉你的应用初见起色
to do once your application has reached the state where you
有模有样的时候
feel like it's kind of shaped up a little bit
你就会开始添砖加瓦  想着怎样好好打造它
is to think about ways that you could change it.
比如说看到此情此景  我就在想
And if I look at this and I just imagine
也许给工具栏再加些CSS
perhaps applying a little CSS to that toolbar
或者是往list里添加些内容
and perhaps adding a little bit more content to the list,
这样仿佛就和Inbox
then I'm really not that far from something
差不多了耶
that looks a lot like Inbox, right.
所有的部件确切的说都是相同的
All the parts remain the exact same,
我们仅仅只是微微调节了一下它们的外观
we're just tweaking slightly the appearance of them-- changing
换换颜色  增加一点儿内容
some colors, adding a little bit more content--
但是我们却获得了非同寻常的体验
but we've now got a very different experience.
而且core-list支持自适应高度
And because core list supports variable height
所以这就这意味着
content-- meaning that our rows don't all
我们不必过分的苛求相同大小
have to be the exact same fixed size--
我们可以试试卡片式风格
we can think about throwing cards inside of here.
而且如果我们这样做的话
And if we do that, then we have an experience that looks kind
体验就会有点儿像Google plus
of like G+.
再一次  我们的模式没有发生变化
And again, none of my markup actually changed.
依旧有一个core-toolbar和paper-icon-button
I still have a core-toolbar, I still have paper-icon-button,
以及paper-menu-button还有header-panel和core-panel 最后还有core-list
still have paper-menu-button, header-panel, core-panel, and core-list.
所以说我们的模式没有变化
So my markup remained the exact same.
唯一发生变化的  就是放在应用里面的
The only thing that changed was the content
那些精彩纷呈的内容
that I'm placing inside of it, which is pretty cool.
我想 这就是composition的力量
Now in my mind, this is the power of composition.
当我们拥有一个饱含优良基因模块的移动端SDK
When we have a mobile SDK that's full of these really
我们能开发出给人以不同体验的非凡应用
good generic building blocks, we can build vastly different
仅仅通过适当的将模块进行组合
experiences just by arranging them differently and tweaking
或者是微微调节
them slightly.
信息量有点儿大
I think that's huge.
好 让我们回到刚才的联系人应用
So let's go back to our contacts app for a second.
我们已经得到了一个基本的页面
We've got the basic pages kind of figured out,
但是我还没有向你展示如何从一个状态移动到
but I haven't really shown you how to move from one state
另一个状态  这对很多人来说是个难点
to the next, and this is a dilemma for a lot of folks.
他们开始构建组件并感到非常兴奋
They start building components, they get really excited,
然后他们把这些组件整合到一个页面里
they throw them together on a page,
然后他们会想该如何从一个状态
and then they're like, how do I go from point A
过渡到了一个状态  就是说该如何做转换呢
to point B. Basically, how do I do transitions?
这是我们正在解决的问题之一
And this is one of those areas where we're still
但是我认为我们已经获得了
working on it, but I think we've got
一些非常酷的东西
some really cool stuff in the pipeline.
这是我之前向你们展示过的我认为很棒的元素
One of the elements that I've shown before which I think
我在它上面放了一个演示用的图案
is really awesome-- I put this little experimental badge on it
虽然这只是个小实验
because it also is a little experimental--
但它是我喜欢展示的非常酷的东西
but it's so freaking cool I like to show it.
这是一个叫做core-animated-pages的元素
It's this element called core-animated-pages,
它提供了一个可组合的系统
which gives you a pluggable system for transitioning
用于从应用的一个状态转换到另一个状态
of one state of your application to the next.
它的基本使用方式是把一些section元素
And basically, the way this works is I
放到core-animated-pages元素中
put some sections inside of my core animated pages.
我配置了它的selected属性
I configure its selected attribute
好告诉它一开始应该显示哪一个section
to tell it which section should be displaying at the time,
我还给它加了一个transitions属性
and I give it a transitions property and I tell it--
transitions属性是
or sorry, transitions attribute to tell it
用来声明从一个状态到另一个状态
which transitions I would like it
要做什么样的转换
to play as it moves from one state to the next.
就像这样  我把他们装好了
And with basically just that I've wired up
这真是非常酷的系统
this is really cool system for animating
在我应用中的不同状态之间实现了动画效果
through different states in my application.
这样在我的应用中标签看起来就是这个样子的
So inside of my app, my markup kind of looks like this.
我得到了构建每个页面的一大堆标签
I've got a whole bunch of markup that makes up every single page
所有这些组装到了一起
and it's all kind of composed together.
那么我现在开始做状态转换
And so the way that I'm going to transition
实际上拿走所有这些标签
from one state to the next is actually take all this markup
然后把应用中的每个section变成一个自定义标签
and turn each section of my application into a custom tag.
保留所有标签  创建一个它的元素
Keep all that markup, make an element out of it.
接着我开始把所有这些自定义元素嵌入到
core-animated-pages元素中
Then I start nesting those elements inside of core-animated-pages.
我从contacts-page开始
So I start with my contacts page.
然后放一个info-page
当你点击联系人的时候出现
I drop in an info page for when you click on a contact
你就实际看到他们的详细信息了
and you actually can see their profile.
所以我在这里创建了一个
叫做fade-scale的转换
So I created a little custom transition here called fade scale.
它作为一个info-page的属性出现
It's on my info page as an attribute.
同时它也作为core-animated-pages元素上
transition属性的属性值
It's also in the transitions attribute for core-animated-pages.
现在当你点击一个联系人时
So now when you click on a contact, which
动画就出现了  如果你返回
is going to animate up, so you're adding there
它就消失了
and then it goes away.
接下来对于添加用户的页面
And again, for the page where I add a user,
基本上也是一样的
it's basically the same thing.
我在这里嵌入那个元素
I nest that element inside of here.
给它加上一个转换属性
I give it a transition.
在animated-pages的transition属性中也加上
I add that transition to animated-pages transitions attribute.
现在我点击浮动按钮  就会弹出
I click on my floating action button now, pops up.
我就可以添加新用户或者返回
I can add a new user if I want and it goes away.
现在我想要和你分享另一个技巧
Now, another tip that I want to share with you
是我在构建这个的时候偶然想到的
is something that I came across as I was building this.
Core animated pages做了这么一件事
Core animated pages does this thing
如果一个元素当前没有被显示
where if an element is not displaying,
它将会被设置为 display none
it's going to make it display none, which can totally
这时如果要计算它的高度或类似的事情
screw it up if it's trying to figure out its height
就有麻烦了
or do anything like that.
所以这里有个叫做
So this magical event here called core animated pages
core-animated-pages-transition-prepare
transition prepare, which is the longest
的世界最长的事件名
this event name in the history of the world.
但是这个事件做了神奇的事情
But this event does magical things
因为它基本上是在你的元素从display none
because it basically fires the moment that your element goes
到display block的时候触发的
from being display none to being display block.
这意味着你可以用它来做所有
And that means that you can then do all the work
你需要确认测量到
that you need to do to make sure that things are measured
正确的高度和类似的事情的事
and have the right height and everything like that.
我再次确信当你看到这个事件时你会觉得
Again, this is one of the things that I'm sure if you see this,
搞什么呀  看起来像便便  我完全同意
you're like dude, that feels like a wart, and I totally agree.
我想你是对的
I think you're right.
这是我们团队
And this is one of the things that I
已经意识到的问题之一
know the team is aware of and we're
我们正在想办法看看是否能消除这个问题
going to work on to see if we can actually smooth this out
这样你就不必做这些自我欺骗的事情了
for people so you don't have to do all that finagling yourself.
但是再一次我想让你注意到这个问题
But again, I wanted to make you aware of it
所以如果你在跟着看这个视频
so if you're following along with this video or something
或者事后想要自己尝试和实现这些
afterwards, you want to try and implement this stuff yourself,
你知道应该如何去做了
you know how to do it.
现在我有了这个网站的所有section
So at this point, I have all the sections of my site together.
它们有动画效果  非常酷的东西
They animate, they do really cool stuff,
但它们仅仅是个动画效果
but really that's just animation.
我们并没有真正地改变状态
We're not really changing the state, per se.
我们还有另一个要点路由没说
We're missing the other half of the puzzle, which is routing,
这经常出现
and this comes up a lot.
开发者总是喜欢问在Polymer中如何实现路由
Developers are always like, how do I do routing in Polymer?
这里Polymer和Webfluenz并没有提供实际的方法
And Polymer and Webfluenz don't really have an opinion here.
我们不会告诉你具体如何做
We're not going to tell you specifically
并不要求你必须怎么做
you have to do routing this way.
事实上这方面有两种处理方式
There's really two ways that you can go about this.
你可以用JavaScript命令式指定
You can do it imperatively in JavaScript
或者你可以用元素声明式地指定
or you can do it declaratively with element.
我将给你展示这两种方法
And so I'm going to show you both approaches,
然后你可以决定你喜欢哪种方式
and you can decide which you prefer.
如果你想用命令式路由
So if you're going the imperative route,
就像这样
looks something like this.
就像看上去一样简单
It's really as simple as just listening
使用一些路由库处理路由改变
for a route change using some sort of routing library.
这里我用的是flatiron库
Here, I'm using flat iron director library,
所以当匹配了一条路由   我告诉
so when I hear a route match, I tell core-animated-pages, hey,
core-animated-pages改变它当前选择的页面
change whichever page is currently selected.
这种方式非常直接
It's pretty straightforward.
用JavaScript方式指定路由有一个好处
Now, one of the nice things about routing in JavaScript
你可以进行细致入微的控制
is it gives you pretty fine grained control if you want it.
如果路由里有参数的话
So if there's parameters in my route,
可以很容易的进行匹配
I can catch those when the route matches.
或者是
I can go fetch more data if I need to
获取更多的数据
and feed that to the page, or I can just
给页面传递参数
pass those parameters to the page itself,
就像这样
be like, here you go, here's the parameter that's coming in,
参数一进来就做出响应
and change.
还有一个有意思的事
So some interesting stuff there.
非常的酷
One thing that is pretty cool, which I wasn't actually using
实际上在我演示时并没有用到
my contacts as I experimented with it.
我想这是一个好主意
I think it's a really cool idea.
未来也许会
It's something that we're probably
应用的更加广泛
going to be using a lot more in the future
这就是lazy loading import
is this notion of lazy loading imports.
我们假设
So actually, let's say you've got part of your site
页面有四五页深
that's four or five pages deep, someone
此刻用户并不一定需要全部的页面
doesn't need all of those components right away.
在Polymer里
There's this mechanism in Polymer
有一个叫Polymer Import的组件
called Polymer Import which you can
用以实现动态加载
use to just sort of dynamically import things.
把它加在路由上
So you can add that to your router.
当路由匹配时
You can say, hey, when that route matches,
就加载一些新的内容
that far away route, let's import some of that new stuff,
期间你可以在这放个加载界面什么的
maybe throw a loading screen up during that time.
当一切准备就绪
And when it's ready, Polymer Import gives us a call back
Polymer会给一个回调改变页面
and we can change that page.
这就是用JavaScript方式指定路由
So that's the JavaScript way of doing it.
你也可以通过
There are also projects out there which do this in markup
元素声明式地指定路由
with elements.
这里有一个由Erik Ringsmuth开发
In particular, there's this really cool one
叫做app router的神奇东西
called app-router by Erik Ringsmuth.
它能帮你处理URL变化
It allows you to handle URL changes
更新应用视图
and update the views in your application.
监测URL的hash变化以及Html的历史API
It handles hashchange URLs, as well as HTMLs history API.
这样就又有一个可选的啦
So you get either flavor that you prefer.
还有一个超棒的事情是
The other cool thing is that it actually already supports
它早已支持core-animate-pags和Polymer import中的lazy importing元素
core-animated pages and doing lazy importing with Polymer import.
在后台就帮你打理好了一切
But it does all that under the hood for you
根本不用你亲自动手
so you don't have to do it yourself.
再一次  两种选择
So again, two options.
挑一个你喜欢的
It really depends on which flavor
我倒是建议你两个都试一试
you prefer, but definitely try both out and see
选一个表现最好的
what you like in your application.
在这一环节  我们把所有的组件都缝合到了一起
So this one, I feel like I have my application pretty sewn up.
为应用添加了很多有趣的动作
It does all sorts of really interesting behaviors.
它看起来棒极了
I'm pretty stoked with the way it looks,
现在是时候专注性能了
and now it's time to focus on performance.
对不起  放错幻灯片了  Performance
Sorry, that's the wrong slide-- performance.
让我们开始吧
There we go.
我喜欢这个表情
I love that lady's face.
人们和Polymer赛跑的领域
One of the areas that people run afoul with Polymer
通常是路由文件的大小
often is the route file size.
你之前八成听到过
You'll even hear this.
Polymer太巨大臃肿了
People will be like, Polymer's too big.
等等之类的话
It's just bloated, whatever.
我们可以通过很多方法来进行优化
And there's some ways that you can mitigate this.
首先就是从x-gif的缔造者
First is this thing that I stole from Glen Maddern, who
Glen Maddern大神那里搞来的
is the creator of x-gif, which is the most important custom
有史以来最重要的custom element
element ever made.
Yeah
Yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
如果你还没领略过x-gif
If you haven't seen x-gif you should take some time
那么一真该去花时间去看一看
and spend it with x-gif.
而致胜的关键法宝
So one really quick win that you can get
就是有条件的加载polyfill
is just conditionally loading the polyfills.
你不必在每个平台上都加载polyfill
You don't have to load the polyfills on every platform.
这是一些支持polyfill的平台
There are platforms that support them.
Chrome  Opera  还有Android上的Chrome
Chrome supports it, Opera supports it, Chrome for Android
Firefox也将很快提供支持
supports it, and hopefully very soon Firefox.
所以我们要做的
So all we're doing here's is just
仅仅是去核实每一个页面在不同标准下
checking to see if the different standards are implemented
能否都能得以正常工作
on the page.
若能  则万事大吉
If they are, we just move right along.
若不能  我们就加载polyfill
If they're not, then we load the polyfills.
这是能为你减少流量的奇技淫巧
So this is an easy way to save yourself quite a bit of kilobytes.
请务必有条件的加载polyfill
Just conditionally load stuff.
这是其一
That's one trick.
还有件事
And the other thing you've got to do
你需要打开你的开发者工具
is you've got to actually pop open the dev tools
实时监视着每一个页面
and you got to make sure that you're inspecting your page.
这里我打开我那个
So I looked at the contacts app after I
引以为豪的联系人应用
built it and was very proud of it.
点击上面的网络面板
I popped open the network panel there
一共有109个请求  有点儿多啊
and I saw that I was making 109 requests-- which is a lot--
并且共加载了943KB
and I'm loading 943 kilobytes of stuff.
而且我这还是没有加载图片
Now, keep in mind, I have excluded the images
仅仅是一些代码
from this network panel, so that's just my code.
我靠  玩脱了
Holy crap, that's a lot.
让我们看看这109个请求都有啥
I recognize that 109 requests for some of you might be concerning.
这里面到底发生了什么
But what's going on there is under the hood,
关键就在于插入的那些element
I'm importing elements.
这些元素具有依赖性
Those elements have dependencies.
它们再引入它们的依赖  如此循环
They're importing their dependencies, and so on and so on.
它们就像一棵树一样
It's basically this whole tree that's
在应用里越长越大
growing out of my application.
为了解决这个问题  我们造了一个叫Vulcanize的工具
And so to mitigate this, we created a tool called Vulcanize.
Vulcanize是一个
And Vulcanize is a module which will actually
把你所有的import都串在一起的工具模块
take all of your imports, concatenate them together,
将所有的JavaScript和CSS
smoosh them all together, take all your JavaScript
都压制到一个文件里
and your CSS, mash it all into one file,
这样应用仅需加载一个文件就可以
and allow you to just load that one thing into your application.
你可以通过nodejs获取这个模块
Now, it is available as a node module,
如果你对此不感冒的话
but if you are not so stoked about doing everything
你也可以通过构建工具Grunt和Gulp
on the command line, it's also available in a Grunt
获取它
task and a Gulp task.
而对于刚才的这个联系人应用  我用的是Grunt
And for the contacts app, I just used the Grunt task.
仅需设置一次  然后放手不管就可以
I set it up once and I just never thought about it again.
简化工作  节省时间
It just runs every time I'm about to push
这太棒了
to production, which is cool.
现在  经过vulcanize化之后
Now, after I Vulcanize and I make
重新把它推送到server上
sure to put my stuff on a server that supports [INAUDIBLE],
应用请求只有3个  效果显著
my application is now three requests, which is a significant change.
而且把文件加载也降低到了114KB  太棒啦
And I've got it down to 114 kilobytes, which is pretty nice.
现在加载的是所有应用代码
Now, this is all the code for my entire application.
包括所有的JavaScript以及CSS
This is all the JavaScript, all the CSS,
以及所有HTML
all the HTML for my entire application.
我们把它降到了114K
So I've got it down to 114 K, and this number
这个数字 在Polymer0.8版本中
gets actually even smaller, much smaller,
还可以变得更小  更简洁  酷毙了
in Polymer 0.8, which is cool.
至此  我们最后要做的
Now, the last thing we've got to do,
就是准备要将其打包
we've got our app to the point where we're
与世界分享我们的应用
ready to put it up there, share it with the world,
但是别忘了确保它能够脱机使用
but we've got to make sure we're thinking about offline.
老生常谈  如果你的移动应用不提供离线支持的话
Because again, if your app doesn't work offline,
怎能谈得上算是移动应用
you really don't have a mobile experience.
今天我们讨论了不少跟Service Worker有关的东西
And I know that we've talked a lot about ServiceWorker
我还是想再说说
today, so I will talk about it again here because it's so
因为它实在是酷的要冒烟儿了
freaking awesome and I'm so excited about it.
我所做的就是把Service Worker添加到应用里面
What I did was I added service worker to this application.
简单粗暴
Pretty straightforward.
看看Service Worker是否存在
I just checked to see if ServiceWorker exists.
存在的话就安上
If it does, I install it.
还有件重要的事要说说
Important thing to note here is that as I'm
在我安装Service Worker时碰到的
installing my ServiceWorker, I've
务必要确保使用root scope
got to make sure that I'm using the root scope so that I can
这样才能在应用顶层捕捉到全部请求
catch any request at sort of the top level of my application.
如果你把ServiceWorker嵌套在子目录里面
If you nest your ServiceWorker inside of a subdirectory
或者其他类似的地方
or something like that, then it's
Service Worker只能捕捉到当前Scope的请求
only going to have access to the request in that scope, which
这糟透了
sort of sucks.
尽可能的把它放在更高的层级
You want to put it high up if you can.
在这个联系人应用里面  在启动的时候
Inside my application, as soon as we boot up,
就尽可能的进行缓存
I just try and cache as much stuff as I can.
你会注意到我在缓存所有element里面
You'll notice that I'm caching the vulcanized bundle of all
vulcanize化的bundle
of my elements.
所以UI才能像丝一般顺滑
So my UI is just like instantly available.
我也缓存了不少来自data Service的初始请求
I'm also caching the initial response from my data service
所以你看到联系人填充了列表
so that there are contacts to populate my list there.
我做的另外一件事
And then the other thing that I did
就是当用户来回滚动时
was as the user is scrolling around,
动态缓存每一个
I'm dynamically caching any sort of image
放在Amazon S3服务器上的图像
that has a host name from S3.amazon.
不管你通过采用avatar头像
So as you pass through an avatar image
还是从Amazon S3服务器获取的方式
and call this S3 response method.
所有的一切  都只是为了获取那个头像
And really, all it's doing is it's fetching that image,
将其通过Service Worker缓存  让Service Worker充当服务端
it's caching it, and then serving up for people.
这样用户使用时就是从Service Worker上面获取相关资源
So as user kind of uses my app, it just consumes things for them.
现在  我们在Chrome Canary版
Now, if we pop this open in Canary
提供了Service Worker的相关支持  开始运行我们的应用
and we've got Service Worker running, we started running our app.
我所要做的
And what I'm doing here is at first,
就是快速的滑到最底部
I'm just racing to the bottom of my application.
注意看  Service Worker并没有开启
And right now, there's no Service Worker in play,
现在正在从网络上一次性加载
and so what it's doing is loading all 300
所有的300个联系人头像
of my contact images at once and just hammering the crap out
of the network.
你可能会说  哦  上帝
And you'll see it's like, oh God,
为毛这样对我
why are you doing this to me.
现在差不多加载完了
And it finally all starts to load in.
现在让我们刷新一下下
Now let's refresh it and see what
看看Service Worker运行会出现什么
happens when ServiceWorker's in play.
关掉Wifi  刷新页面
Let's turn our Wi-Fi off, refresh the page.
看Network这一栏
You'll see here over in the column
我们所有的素材都来自Service Worker的缓存
that our assets are now coming from ServiceWorker.
再一次滑到最底部
So I race to the bottom of my application.
立等可现有木有
All those things are just coming in immediately.
没有丝毫的延迟  太棒了
There's no wait on those assets, which is really cool.
掌声
[APPLAUSE]
好  基本齐活儿
So, wrap up.
我们从中学到了什么呢
What did we learn?
为了构建你的应用
For structuring your application,
为了构建你的UI
for structuring your UI, you've got the core and the paper
你学会了使用了core和paper elements
elements.
所以你才能把这些合成到一起
So you can compose those together
只为创作出最佳的移动应用体验
to make a really awesome mobile experience.
为了让应用的一个状态过渡到另外一个状态
From moving from one state of your application to the next,
你学会了如何运用core-animated-pages
you've got core-animated-pages, and you've also
学会了如何用命令式和声明式指定路由
got imperative or declarative routing.
二者随你爱好  任选其一
Kind of depends on how you like to do that.
出于性能的考虑  有选择的加载polyfill
For performance, conditional polyfills.
最重要的是vulcanize化所有的一切
And most importantly, vulcanize all the things.
使用Vulcanize尽可能的将其打包
Use Vulcanize to bundle up as much as you possibly can.
能为你省很多事
It'll save you a lot.
另外  还应该考虑研究延迟加载
Also, consider exploring lazy loading.
这也是我们一直试图弄明白的事情之一
It's one of those things that we're still
什么是合适的模式
trying to figure out what's the right pattern, what's
什么才是合适的UI
the right UX there.
我想在未来
But it's something that I think we'll
我们会看到更多生动的例子
be seeing a lot more in the future,
尤其是在Polymer世界
especially in the world of Polymer.
最后  关于应用的离线支持  Service Worker会为你保驾护航
Lastly, for offline, ServiceWorker's got your back.
学会在不同的浏览器上玩耍你的应用
So as that starts to land in the various browsers--
即使在今天  尽情的演示吧
I mean, even today, experiment with it.
打开不同的浏览器  放入你的App
As it starts to land in various browsers, put it in your app.
这感觉棒极啦
It's going to be really awesome.
如果你仍对这款联系人应用意犹未尽的话
If you want to play around with this contacts app,
你可以在Github上找到它
it's available up on the GitHubs.
它依旧会有Bug  为了让其变得更加完善
It totally has a lot of bugs, so please
所以请不吝指教  提交bug report  尽情的pull requests
file bug reports, but even better, submit pull requests.
如果你想了解更多关于Polymer
If you want to learn more about Polymer
或者你对这一切都充满激情
and you're just excited by everything
正如今天下午Matt所说
you've seen this afternoon, as Matt mentioned,
我们在世界各地都有举办Polymer活动
we're running Polymer events all over the world.
我们称之为Polytechnics
We call these Polytechnics.
我看见你们当中有穿Polymer shirt  这非常的酷
I see some of you wearing the shirts, which means you are cool.
你可以登陆itshackademic.com  找到离你最近的Polytech
If you go to itshackademic.com, you can find a Polytechnic near you.
如果你想加入其中
If you want to participate in one,
亦或是想自己举办一个  无论如何
maybe you want to run your own, whatever,
都是触手可及
all the material is up there.
若你自己已经举办了一个  烦请让我知道
If you set one up, please let me know.
我好帮你宣传一番  等等
Tweet about it, whatever.
这非常的棒  你们都该去看一看
It's freaking awesome, so you should all go check it out.
当然  别忘了Polymer-project.org
Most importantly, polymer-project.org.
每时每刻
As you've all been sitting here, we've actually secretly
我们都在秘密更新
been updating the website.
在那里你将会有一个全新的体验
So there's kind of a new experience there.
删繁就简
It's just a slight-- it's just a nicer coat of paint.
至臻至美
It's not a full blown reboot of the site,
而所有一切
but now it's a lot easier to find the content
都触手可得
that you're looking for.
如果你想要入门Polymer
The getting started experience is a lot easier if you just
这非常的简单
want to get up and running with Polymer,
欢迎来到明天世界  赶快到polymer网站看一看相关教程吧
so definitely check out the site, go through some of the tutorials.
并且  我也期待大家所创造出的非凡作品
And I'm looking forward to seeing all the really cool
再一次  感谢大家
stuff that you guys build, so thanks.
掌声